Aes.
艾斯…
Show me what you got.
让我看看你的本事吧
Double-Headed Aerkos.
双头的亚格斯
Aes, why?
艾斯 为什么
Answer me.
回答我
You are always like that.
你总是这样…
Why don't you understand me?
为何不理解我的心
Why can't you listen to me?
为何你听不进我的声音
Unfortunately, I'm not cut out to be a revolutionary.
很遗憾 我不适合当革命家呢
You weakling!
你这个软弱之徒
Once you guys lose your cool, this place is going to be ruined.
打得激烈一点就变成这样了
I've been waiting for you for so long.
等你们很久了
I'll meet you there.
我也过去跟你们会合
Prepare that.
准备一下那个吧
Anti-phaser, ready.
反相位振动器 准备
(Metallic Rouge)
《金属口红》
Deputy Director, we have no time.
次长 请快过来
Rouge.
露琼
Brother, don't come over.
哥哥 不可以过来
Long time no see.
一阵子不见
You're in high office now.
你变得挺有气概的嘛
You haven't changed at all.
你倒是没什么变呢
Grauphon.
格劳芬
We
我们…
can't change.
是不会改变的
Look.
看看吧
Look at the city you built
你们建立的城池
that is falling in flames.
倒塌在烈焰之中的模样
You still talk in genteel way.
那夸张的用词也是老样子
Shut up.
闭上你的那张嘴
Listen to the sound of destruction.
听听破灭木灵的声音吧
Rouge Redstar.
露琼・雷德斯塔
Use your id to exchange for his life.
用你的伊德 来换回他的命吧
Don't hurt my brother.
不要对哥哥出手
Sad slayer.
悲哀的杀戮者
The girl as a fratricide.
身为同胞杀手的女孩啊
Give me your soul.
把你的灵魂交出来吧
Jet Black Noir.
漆黑的诺瓦尔
Eden Varock.
伊甸・维洛克
I'd like you to call me by this name if you can.
可以的话 我希望你能用这个名字来叫我呢
Eden.
伊甸
I'll spare your life this time.
这次先饶你一命
I can't believe you stood up to protect this fratricide.
居然挺身保护这个同胞杀手
Is Eva's daughter that important?
艾娃的女儿就那么重要吗
I can't bear to see you like this.
你这副模样实在是不忍直视
I got all pieces.
棋子都到齐了
Give me back my brother.
把哥哥还给我
The time has come.
时候到了
That's the Usurper's landing ship.
是篡夺者的登陆舰
Go.
快去…
He…
他是…
He's still alive!
居然还活着啊
Gene.
吉恩
Go.
快去…
Rouge.
露琼…
You are that…
你是刚刚的…
Looks like you can fight me.
这副模样的话就能战斗了吧
Come on, let's fight.
来吧 与我一战
Step aside.
让开
So you finally want to fight, right?
总算是想打了是吧
Gene.
吉恩
Don't be distracted, sister.
别东张西望哦 姐姐
Why are you stopping me?
为什么要妨碍我
Just like that, Metal Rouge.
就是这样 钢铁露琼
You are the opponent I'm supposed to knock out.
这才是我应当击倒的对手
Are they on par with each other?
不相上下吗
They are resonating with each other.
彼此正在产生共振
They might really be sisters.
她们两个搞不好真的是姐妹
If we used the anti-phaser now,
这种状态下使用反相位振动器的话
it's not just blue guy, even Rouge would be in danger.
不只是蓝色家伙 连露琼也会有危险…
Rouge.
露琼
You reverse the phase of the output.
将输出的相位倒转过来
Reverse the phase.
倒转相位
Don't ignore me.
不要不理我
You said something weird again.
又说一些莫名其妙的话…
I told you not to be distracted.
我说过不要东张西望
Oh my, what are you doing?
真是的 你在搞什么啦
It's all because you're talking to me.
还不是因为你在跟我讲话
Anyway, just do it.
总之快点就对了
Do as I say, trust me.
照我的话去做 相信我
No way.
鬼才相信你
Trust me.
相信我
Just trust me.
相信我吧
Oh my.
真是的
You're so noisy.
啰哩叭嗦地吵死了
What did you say?
你刚刚说把相位怎样
Reverse the phase.
倒转
Concentrate.
集中精神
Imagine yourself deforming into a Gladiator again.
想象自己再度变形为斗士
What? I've already deformed.
什么 我已经变了啊
Do it again.
再做一次
Come on, concentrate.
来 集中精神
Oh my.
真是的…
Concentrate.
集中精神…
-W-What are you doing? -Concentrate.
-你…你在做什么 -集中精神…
Concentrate.
集中精神…
-Don't play tricks… -Concentrate.
-耍这种小聪明 -集中精神…
-Destroy…
-破坏
Concentrate.
集中精神…
Deform.
变形
What happened?
发生什么事了
When the two of them deform into
她们两个
Gladiator mode, the generator output frequency characteristics are the same.
变形为斗士模式时的 发电机输出频率特性是一模一样的
What?
什么
So I think reversing the phase of Rouge's output frequency
所以我想 只要将露琼的输出频率 倒转并击出的话
might neutralize each other's energy.
应该就能让彼此的能量消散才对
I don't get it at all.
完全听不懂
It's their two forces neutralizing each other's energy.
就是让她们的力量互相抵消啦
The principle is the same as that of the anti-phaser.
原理就跟 这具反相位振动器是一样的
However,
不过啊
I'm so glad my method worked.
方法奏效真是太好了
Aren't you being too result-oriented?
这样不会太过结果论吗
It's great anyway.
结果论很好啊
There's something I want you to know.
我有事想让你知道
Me too.
我也是…
I want to ask you something.
有话想要问你
Gene.
吉恩…
(Episode 9: The Ones Who Visited)
(9 来访者们)
You two make a good team.
你们是对好搭档
Hmm.
嗯
The two of you
你们两个
should have a good talk.
要好好谈谈哦
BREAKING NEWS About last night's terror attack
(突发新闻) 昨晚发生的
MASS TERROR ATTACK ON ALETHEIA on Aletheia by an armed group,
(真理部遭遇大规模恐怖攻击) 武装组织对真理部进行的恐怖行动
-How is the Sleeping Princess? -nothing is clear now.
-睡美人的情况如何 -现在一切尚不明朗
According to unconfirmed reports…
根据未确认情报…
She's still in a coma.
依然在昏迷状态
Those guys must be our gods by now.
那些家伙 现在应该是我们的神了吧
The Visitors are not gods.
来访者不是神
They are the first extraterrestrial intellectual life
他们是距今40年前
that humans came into contact with 40 years ago.
人类首次接触到的地球外生命体
They are aliens.
也就是外星人
Even now, only a few of the big shots get to see them,
就算是现在 也只有小部分的大人物 能够见到他们的真身
yet they generously share their super technology with us.
然而他们却大方地向我们分享 自己所拥的超科技
How is that any different from gods?
这跟神有什么两样
However, from the perspective of Neans,
不过 从涅安的角度来看
the humans who created them are more like gods.
制造他们出来的人类 还比较像是神吧
In fact, those who created them
实质上制造出他们的
were Roy Junghardt and Eva Kristella.
是罗伊・容格哈特 与艾娃・克利丝缇勒两位博士
However,
然而
the initial Neans they crafted,
他们打造出来的初始涅安
which are the Proto-Neans,
也就是原形涅安
are very different from the current mass-production models.
跟现行的量产型涅安 是完全不同的存在就是了
Immortal Nine.
不朽九人…
They possess capabilities surpassing those of humans.
他们是蕴含超越人类可能性的存在
I can't believe they created something like this.
居然做出这种东西…
From my point of view, it's really disturbing.
从我的角度来看 这可真是令人困扰到不行啊
What?
咦…
W-What are you doing?
你…你在做什么啦
This?
你说这个啊
If I didn't wear it, people would know I'm not a human.
要是不穿的话 不就会被人发现我不是人类了吗
What?
什么…
Naomi, aren't you a human?
直美你不是人类吗
Naomi Orthmann is not a human,
直美・奥德曼并不是人类
but a Contact Nean that the Visitors created for making contact with humans.
而是来访者为了与人类接触 所制造来的沟通型涅安
That is me.
也就是我
Haven't I told you?
我没说过吗
Not at all.
完全没有
That's because you never asked.
那是因为你没问我吧
You have too many secrets.
你的秘密也太多了吧
All right, what are we doing here?
好了 我们来这里做什么
I've said it.
我不是说过了吗
There's something I want you to know.
我有事想让你知道
Stop beating around the bush.
拐弯抹角
Just say it.
赶快说啦
They want to talk to you in person.
他们想要亲自跟你说吧
I don't have time.
现在没时间慢慢来了
Here they are.
来了
They are the X Noah.
他们是杰诺亚
Earthlings call them Visitors.
地球人将其称为"来访者"的存在
Are
他们…
they mermaids?
是人鱼吗
In the past, we X Noah also had a form similar to humans.
过去 我们杰诺亚 也拥有着与人类相似的形态
In order to adapt to the interstellar travel environment,
为了适应恒星间航行环境
it took us generations to evolve into
耗时数个世代实现进化
what we are today.
成为了如今的形态
What?
咦…
They thought you asked a question.
他们以为你在问他们问题
I bring Rouge Redstar here,
我将露琼・雷德斯塔
and her code name is Metal Rouge.
代号"钢铁露琼"带过来了
Got it.
了解
First.
First
First?
First?
Who is that?
是指谁啊
I am the first Nean that X Noah has created in imitation of the Earthling,
我是杰诺亚模仿地球人 所制造出来的第一具涅安
so I'm called First.
所以叫First
And now, her name is Naomi Orthmann.
而现在 她的名字叫直美・奥德曼
Your real name is First?
你的本名叫First啊
I am Naomi Orthmann.
我是直美・奥德曼
What?
嗯?
The first Nean.
第一具涅安…
Well.
咦
How long ago did the Visitors come to Earth?
来访者是多久前来到地球的啊
What?
啊…
What are you trying to say?
你想说什么
I thought you are only a little older than me.
我还以为你只比我大一点点呢…
Do you want to show some respect to me?
你想跟我说敬语吗
Resonating with each other.
彼此共鸣
Meaningless conformity.
无意义的同调
Excessive sync.
过度同步
It is speculated that First's thinking patterns have changed
推测为与露琼・雷德斯塔一同行动
as a result of working with Rouge Redstar.
导致First的思考模式产生变化
But she still has logical judgment,
但仍以合理性做为其判断标准
posing no obstacles to the mission.
对任务之进行并无障碍
Bringing Rouge Redstar here is a logical judgment.
将露琼・雷德斯塔带至这里 是为合理判断
Staying aboard this ship
留在这艘舰内为合理判断
What they mean is you're staying here until it's over.
意思是说 在事情结束前 你要留在这里
What?
什么
Your id has the key information to interpret Code Eve.
你的伊德里 有着解读CODE EVE的关键资讯
Jill…
吉儿…
Silvia has said the same thing.
希尔维雅也说过这种话
Really?
这是真的吗
Yes.
真的
So you'll be safer here.
所以你待在这里会比较安全
Are you going to lock me up?
是要把我关起来吗
Did you betray me again?
你又背叛我了吗
Visitors will not interfere with the actions of Earthlings,
来访者不会干涉地球人的行为
or restrict your movements.
也不会限制你的行动
It's safest for you to stay here.
待在这里 对你是最安全的
Safe.
安全…
Since you will not interfere,
既然不会干涉
Nean and Code Eve are none of your business, right?
那涅安与CODE EVE 不就都与你们无关了吗
It is speculated that Usurpers are involved behind Alter.
推测奥塔背后有篡夺者参与其中
Once Code Eve is activated,
CODE EVE一旦启动
all Neans will be liberated,
所有涅安将会获得解放
and be no longer controllable.
无法再加以控制
Visitors believe that
来访者认为
Usurpers will take advantage of the chaos to start the war again.
篡夺者会趁着混乱之际再度开战
The Usurpers' target is the solar system.
篡夺者的目标是这个太阳系
They wish to eliminate Visitors and humans to seize a planet.
他们想消灭来访者与人类 夺下某颗星球
And Silvia and others are on that planet as well.
而希尔维雅他们 也在那颗星球上
Venus?
金星吗
Good answer.
答得好
It's the planet with the most Neans in the current solar system.
现今太阳系中 存在最多涅安的星球
I see.
原来如此
This is the perfect place to base your resistance.
是最适合用来当作 你们反抗根据地的地点
More than this,
不只是这样
we Neans were born for that planet,
我们涅安是为了那颗星球而诞生的
so there's no better place
再没有比那个星球
to start over than on that planet.
更适合拿来当作 重新开始的新天地了吧
Neans were born for Venus.
涅安是为了金星而诞生
What does it mean?
这是什么意思
We X Noah have lost our home planet.
我们杰诺亚失去了母星
In search of a second homeland,
为了找寻第二个故乡
we've travelled endlessly through time.
在永久的时光中不断旅行
And then we arrived at this star system.
然后抵达了这颗恒星系
We have entered into a contract with the Earthlings.
与地球人缔结了契约
X Noah has provided humans with technology beyond their capabilities.
杰诺亚提供给人类 超乎其科技能力的技术
And humans have offered a planet where X Noah can survive in its original form.
人类则提供杰诺亚在原始形态下 得以生存的星球
That is Venus.
那就是金星
Together, we have transformed the planet.
一同改造该星球
The humans have agreed to let us migrate to Venus.
人类同意让我族移居金星
Neans serve as the labor force for this project.
涅安就是这项工程的劳动力
They were created through the technology provided by X Noah.
是以杰诺亚提供的技术 制造出来的存在
What?
咦
Wait.
等一下
Are you teaching humans how to create Neans in order to get Venus?
你们是为了得到金星 所以教人类如何制造涅安吗
The humans let Neans work on Venus
人类因为得到了你们提供的技术
because of the technology you provided.
所以才能让涅安在金星工作
And now the Usurpers want Neans to rebel,
然后现在篡夺者想让涅安造反
and then take advantage of that…
再趁那个时候…
The Junoid, whom the humans call Usurpers, are extremely dangerous.
人类将其称为"篡夺者" 的由诺伊德是极为危险的存在
They share the same origin as us,
他们与我们杰诺亚根出同源
yet evolved for the worse, becoming a destroyer of civilization.
却往坏的方向进化 成为了文明破坏者
The Junoid also wants to get Venus.
由诺伊德也想得到金星
As long as they're under human control,
只要还在人类的管理之下
Neans will be a force against Junoid.
涅安就能成为对抗由诺伊德的战力
What?
那是怎样
Both humans and you are using Neans
无论是人类或是你们 都在利用涅安
and making them work or fight like tools.
不是像工具般工作 就是去战斗
Neans were created for this.
涅安就是为此而生的存在
We agree that this is their logical value.
我认为此为合理的存在价值
Logical…
合理…
But such things…
但是这种事…
Such things…
这种事…
Are you kidding me?
开什么玩笑
VENUS
(金星)
How's Venus?
金星现在情况如何
Any message from the Planetary Development Corporation?
行星开发公团有什么消息吗
Minister.
部长
A message from the Orbital Outer Office.
轨道外公部传来消息
JUPITER SPHERE The Usurpers at Jupiter has made a move.
(木星圈) 位于木星的篡夺者有动作了
Are they going to attack at the same time?
同时发动攻击吗
The enemies are on the move.
敌人的本体有动作了
Enter into Defcon 1 against the Usurpers.
进入对篡夺者一级戒备状态
Hey, are they going to start another war?
喂…又要开战了吗
I don't have any guests today.
今天没有客人预定来访
You are…
你是…
Hi.
嗨…
Now it's my turn to ask questions.
再来换我提问了
Why did you betray me?
你为什么要背叛我
Why did you hand me over to the Ochrona?
为什么要将我交给守护局
Well…
这个嘛…
Explain it.
说清楚啦
Because I thought it's the safest thing to do.
因为我认为那是最安全的做法
If not, you would have been disassembled by now.
不这么做的话 你早就被人解体了
Can't you discuss it with me beforehand?
擅自下判断前能先跟我讨论一下吗
Sorry.
对不挤
Let me hit you once.
让我揍一下
What?
咦
Do you have any idea how bad that makes me feel?
你知道我有多难受吗
I was thrown into strange water,
被人丢进奇怪的水里
-and my Nectar was almost gone. -Okay.
-涅克托差点就没了 -好啦…
-You said something weird like phase. -I get it.
-又讲什么相位等等我听不懂的东西 -我明白了 我知道了啦
Don't hit me hard.
要轻一点 轻轻的哦
I'm not as…
我跟你不一…
It hurts.
好痛…
You…
你真的是…
I'm not as strong as you.
我跟你不一样 没那么强壮啦…
How can you punch me with your fist?
是说你怎么可以用拳头揍啦
Will you come with me?
你会跟我一起去吧
After all, without me, you'll barely survive.
毕竟没有我 你会九死一生嘛
Annoying!
少啰嗦
That's it. I'm leaving.
事情就是这样 我要离开了
Where are you going?
你要去哪里
Venus, of course.
当然是金星了
It's dangerous.
危险
It is a logical judgement to have Rouge Redstar stay here.
露琼・雷德斯塔留在此地 才是合理判断
I suggest you stay here.
建议你留在这里
Indeed.
的确
Even the Usurpers, Junoid can't easily attack this orbital city.
就算是篡夺者 由诺伊德 也无法轻易对这个轨道城出手
As long as Rouge Redstar stays here,
只要露琼・雷德斯塔留在这里
Code Eve wouldn't be activated, so it's very safe.
就能确保CODE EVE不会启动 可以说是非常安全
Correct.
没错
But,
但是
now Venus could fall into the hands of Junoid.
如今金星 有可能落入由诺伊德的手中
Placing our bets on Rouge Redstar and letting her solve this with her abilities
将赌注押在露琼・雷德斯塔身上 让她以所拥有的能力解决这件事
is also a logical judgment from my perspective.
我认为这项建言 也不失为一个合理的判断
X Noah can't interfere with any individual's will to act.
杰诺亚无法干涉个人行为意志
Therefore, I agree to your proposal.
故在此同意你的提议
Let's start discussing what's the best solution if First's proposal fails.
开始讨论First的提议失败状况下 最佳对策为何
Thank you all.
谢谢你们
Then I'll go with her and do everything I can to help her.
那么我将与露琼・雷德斯塔同行 全力协助她
We do not agree First go to Venus.
不同意让First前往金星
First's mission is limited to contact and negotiation with the Earthlings.
First的任务只限定于 跟地球人的接触与交涉
Combat is not part of your mission.
战斗不在你的任务范围里
I'm here to ask you to take a leave of absence.
我在此向各位要求"休假"
Leave of absence?
"休假"
I've never asked for a break since I was created.
我从出厂以来从没要求过要休息
Science also confirms
科学也证实
proper leave helps improve work efficiency.
适当的休假有助于提升劳动效率
Here is the relevant data.
这是相关资料
We agree to its rationale.
同意其合理性
Thank you.
感谢
I can't believe you can deal with those things.
真亏你能跟那些东西打交道啊
I'm used to it, after all.
毕竟也习惯了嘛
But,
不过啊
when I'm on a leave, I hope they can pay me as usual.
我休假时 那群人应该会照常付我薪水吧
So,
那么…
how are we supposed to get to Venus?
我们要怎么去金星呢
Well…
这个嘛…
See, we have a way.
你看 这不是有办法了吗
What?
嗯?
Hi.
嗨